hi and welcome to new every day my name
嗨，欢迎新的每一天我的名字
is jen and my name is Carrie and on
是jen，我的名字是Carrie
today's show we are looking at part two
今天的节目我们正在看第二部分
of our adventure in the ark encounter in
我们在约克遇到的冒险经历
Kentucky United States the station
肯塔基州美国站
[Music]
[音乐]
Oh
哦
hello and welcome back we are so glad
你好，欢迎回来，我们很高兴
that you tuned into new every day thank
你每天都调到新的感谢
you so much for our faithful viewers
你非常忠实于我们忠实的观众
from around the world it's always
来自世界各地的，它总是
amazing to me Jenn when I hear about
令人惊异的是我和Jenn当我听到有关
people who are tuning in from all sorts
从各种各样调整的人
of different countries across the globe
世界各地的国家
yes really amazing so thank you if you
是真的太棒了所以谢谢你，如果 你
would like to go to our website new
我 想去 新网站
everyday TV you can check out all sorts
日常电视，你可以看看 各种各样的
of information past episodes go to our
过去的情节信息转到我们的
partners page and check out the our
合作伙伴页面并查看我们的
supporters if you want to buy something
支持者，如果你想买东西
on amazon do it the favor and just go to
在亚马逊做它的好处，只是去
our parts page and click on it through
我们的 零件页面并点击 它
there and then we get a fortune of that
在那里，然后我们得到了一大笔财富
to help support the show so thank you so
帮助支持节目所以谢谢你
much so jumping back in Gen yes because
所以跳回Gen是因为
last week we ended off with the story
上周我们结束了这个故事
coming to a point where the earth had
到了地球的地步
become the people of the earth have
成为地球 人民
become so wicked that it said and it
变得如此邪恶，以至于它说
greedy God that he had even made people
贪得无厌的上帝， 他甚至 造了人
which is just like her and yet Noah
这就像她，但诺亚
what's found see and so God and this is
什么样的发现 看 ，因此上帝，这是
what I love about the heart god Carrie
我喜欢心灵之神嘉莉
is that because God loves us at his
是因为上帝爱他们
creation he will always make way for us
创造他将永远为我们让路
he will always make away from in a
他将永远地远离一个人
physical
物理
Noah was found right and so as a way of
诺亚被发现是正确的，所以作为一种方式
state because he had a covenant with
国家，因为他有一个约
creation as well right from the very
创造就好了
beginning he made a covenant with
从他开始与他立约
creation and so by providing an
通过提供一个
opportunity with Noah was a dozen of the
诺亚的机会是十几个
ark it was God being faithful to his
方舟是上帝忠于他的
covenant with gracious an open
与仁慈开放的契约
relationship with no one and so and we
没有人和我们的关系
got talking about this work of that cup
谈论那个 杯子的这项工作
a picture of his huge door because what
因为什么 ，他巨大的门的照片
I love about the store is it says and
我喜欢这家商店
God brought the animals to the ark they
上帝把动物 带到了他们的方舟
would have come in that door I love the
我会喜欢上那扇门
fact that if it's God brought the
事实上，如果它是上帝带来的
animals to the arc they hard to round
动物电弧他们很难圆
them all up really it would because they
它们真的很棒，因为它们
would have had to go all over the world
本来不得不去世界各地
but then offend God close the door don't
但后来冒犯上帝关上门不
work for like okay I can always just
为了好的工作，我总能做到
read it okay yeah good part of the story
读它没关系， 这是故事的 一部分
God didn't we brought on the closed door
上帝不是我们带上了关门
but what's really cool if you have to
但是如果你不得不这么做真的很酷
think about what is that
想想那是什么
Noah being righteous was provided a
诺亚是正义的提供了一个
place of safety
安全的地方
from the judgement of mankind in the US
来自美国 人类的判断
and then when the time was right the
然后当时间到了
tool was opening and no allowed to have
工具正在打开，不允许有
new life they were an ass now I'm
新生活他们现在是我的屁股
allowed to have denied like that just
允许这样拒绝
blows me away and the fact is that is an
把我吹走了，事实是这是一个
image of what Christ did fraud and we
基督欺诈和我们的形象
talked a little bit about what that was
谈了一下这是什么
and the fact that come in the book of
以及进入书中的事实
John Jesus says what do you have value
约翰耶稣说你有什么价值
yeah it's in John chapter 10 and Jesus
是的，这是约翰福音第10章和耶稣
says
说
most assuredly I say to you he does not
我肯定会告诉你他 没有
enter the sheepfold by the door but
在门口进入羊圈但是
climbs up some other way the same
以其他方式爬上去
indices in a robber but he who entered
强盗的指数，但进入的人
by the door is the Shepherd of the Sheep
通过门口就是羊的牧人
to him the doorkeeper opens and the
对他来说，门卫打开了
sheep hear his voice and he calls his
羊听到他的声音， 他打电话给他
own sheep by name and leads them out and
按名称拥有羊并将它们引出来
when he brings out his own sheep he goes
当他带出自己的羊时，他就去了
before them and the Sheep follow him for
在他们面前，绵羊跟着他
they know his voice and then it could
他们知道他的声音然后就可以了
skip down in G 2 verse 7 Jesus says most
在G 2第7节中跳过耶稣 说的最多
assuredly I think you I am the door of
当然，我认为你是我的大门
the Sheep all deliver keen for me are
绵羊都热衷于我
thieves and robbers because she did not
小偷和劫匪，因为她没有
hear them I am the door if anyone enters
听到他们如果有人进来，我就是门
by me he will be saved and go in and out
通过我，他将得到拯救并进出
and find pasture so it's interesting
并找到牧场，这很有趣
about that is that the sheet pan would
关于那就是平底锅会
be around structure with an opening and
是围绕结构具有开口和
the shepherd would lie in the opening
牧羊人会躺在开口处
and so when it says it literally says I
所以当它说它字面上说我
asked the door I didn't know that yes so
问门，我不知道是的
they can only get out of kingdom by the
他们只能离开王国
way yeah or if he put them in yes like
方式是的，或者如果他把它们放在是的话
he is literally the door work and that's
他确实是 门工作的
why says you can only enter by me isn't
为什么说你只能通过我进入不是
that amazing I can no one yeah without a
很神奇，我可以没有一个耶无
mess in the deployer you can know that
你 可以知道， 在部署者中弄得一团糟
did your thunder I
你的雷声我
circles Patrick oh okay that is a really
帕特里克哦，好吧，这 是真的
amazing and so how they set up this
太棒了，所以他们如何建立这个
description of the door in the Ark
方舟门的描述
Encounter was at first they had it an
邂逅起初他们有一个
animatronic model of one of the Sun why
其中一个太阳为什么的电子动画模型
yep and she's sweeping the floor and it
是的，她正在席卷地板
talks about pondering the tough
谈论对艰难的思考
questions like why did God just the
像上帝为什么这样的问题
earth why was there a flood why did all
为什么所有人都有洪水？
people have to die what do all of these
人们不得不死于所有这些
things mean yes and then you see her
事情意味着是，然后你看到了她
pondering and sleeping and the display
思考，睡觉和显示
encourages you to think about these
鼓励你思考这些
things and then it shares the story of
事情，然后它分享的故事
how all have sinned and fallen short of
所有人都犯了罪并且没有犯罪
the glory of God and therefore we
上帝的荣耀，因此我们
actually deserved odd jobs judgment on
实际上应该做出奇怪的工作判断
our spin against him and leading up to
我们反对他，并导致
that it showed what one sin caused
它显示了一个罪所造成的
everyone to do and how people became so
每个人都要做， 以及人们如何变得如此
wicked the gaudiya to cleanse the world
邪恶的高迪亚清洗世界
with his judgment and wash away the
他的判断和冲走了
payment sent to me and so right beside
付款发送给我，就在旁边
this display is this massive massive
这个显示是巨大的
door okay so big and Jesus says that I
门好可以这么大，耶稣说我
am the door and he also says I stand at
我是门，他也说我站在那里
the door and not and we choose to open
门而不是我们选择打开
that door and walk through it we have
那扇门， 我们走过它
the free will to do it and that separate
自由意志去做和分开
open again when the handle was there
手柄在那里时再次打开
it's like if you saw that I am choosing
就像你看到我选择的那样
whether I'm going to get in the ark and
我是否准备进入方舟和
be saved from the form I mean you can
从我的意思是你可以保存的形式
draw so many parallels that railing not
画出如此多的平行线，而不是栏杆
only salvation from sin but also like in
只有从罪中得救，但也喜欢在罪中
storms a life am I going to choose to
我将选择 参加一场生活
open that door am I going to say to
打开那扇门，我要说
Jesus I believe that you are able to be
耶稣我相信你能 成为
more than an opportunity
不仅仅是机会
to be like peace that passes
过得像和平一样
understanding during the forms of life
在生活形式中的理解
but I also believe that when all is said
但我也相信 ，一切都说了
and done when the world has been
并在世界成就时完成
stripped away when my life is finished
我的生命结束后被剥夺了
that the only reason that I am going to
这是我要的唯一原因
make it to be with God in heaven is
在天堂与上帝同在
because Jesus was that door that he laid
因为耶稣是他铺设的门
he laid down he laid down to that whole
他放下了他放下的那一切
life so as we go to commercial break
生活，所以我们去商业休息
what I want you to think about is have I
我想让你想到的是我
opens door to Christ in my life have I
我有生命，打开基督的大门
surrendered my life to Christ we back in
把我的生命交给了我们回来的基督
Jeff Weston Yemen you're building a
杰夫韦斯顿也门你正在建设 一个
brand new beautiful website what are you
全新的美丽网站你是什么
all right you're terrible actor what
好吧，你是一个可怕的演员
this we're acting comes into play oh I
这个我们正在发挥作用哦我
don't know what our Arctic you're
不知道你的北极是什么
supposed to act okay I'm building a
应该行动好我正在建立一个
really cool website are you building a
真的很酷的网站，你建立一个
really cool website you need hosting one
非常酷的网站，你需要托管一个
of the things about a hosting account is
关于托管帐户的事情是
you don't want to have limitations put
你不希望有限制
on your website it's sure how much hard
在你的网站上，它确定有多难
drive space you have how many email
驱动器空间你有多少电子邮件
accounts how many domains can point to
帐户可以指向多少个域
it well we've got an amazing deal for
好吧，我们有一个惊人的交易
you for a very limited time cat five dot
你有一个非常有限的时间猫五点
TV / dreamhost for just five dollars and
电视/梦想家只需五美元
a bit of change per month you are going
你每个月都会 有一点变化
to get unlimited web site hosting
获得无限的网站托管
unlimited email accounts on that hosting
该主机上的无限电子邮件帐户
service you are also going to receive a
服务你也会收到一个
free domain name the roof of your own
免费域名你自己的屋顶
comm site to put that amazing website
comm网站把这个惊人的网站
that you've been working on on there if
你曾经在那里工作过
you run if you want to build a wordpress
你运行，如果你想建立一个wordpress
site fine sign up cat five gb flash
网站精美报名猫五gb闪存
dream home don't put a little paper
梦想家不要放一点纸
sorry just don't do it but hey it's a
抱歉，不要这样做，但嘿，这是一个
great deal folk festival you're going to
你要去的很多民间节日
find five dollars and change per month
找到五美元，每月更换一次
go to cap five dot TV / dreamhost
去盖五点电视/ dreamhost
welcome back to new every day we're in
我们每天都欢迎回到新的一年
mid discussion about how
中间讨论如何
is the door to salvation and forgiveness
是拯救和宽恕的大门
of sins and how in the ark there was one
罪孽如何在方舟中有一个
door that the animals and the people
门那动物和人民
could go into in God closed door and
可以进入神闭门而且
then when the ark landed he opened the
然后当方舟落地时，他打开了
door and they could go out and start a
门，他们可以出去开始了
new life and so Jen we were just trying
新生活，所以Jen我们只是在尝试
some other parallels do that because
其他一些相似之处是因为
we've talked a few times about the fact
我们已经谈过几次关于 事实
that Abraham was the only righteous man
亚伯拉罕是唯一正义的人
and gob squad at the ark Noah Noah Noah
在诺亚诺亚诺亚方舟的gob小队
was usually behave and was there justice
通常表现得很正常
and and God provide the art to save him
并且上帝提供拯救他的艺术
when we choose and that was the question
当我们选择时，这就是问题所在
I left to it before he went to break is
在他休息之前，我离开了它
you know where he at Jesus having chosen
你知道他在耶稣所选择的地方
to open the door to him and that's one
打开他的门，那是一个
of the things I love about that passage
关于那段话我喜欢的事情
in revelation behold I stand at the door
在启示中，我站在门口
and knock anyone who opens the door I
敲门打开门的人我
will come in and he and I and my father
将进来，他和我， 我的父亲
will eat with him and he with odds like
他会和他一起吃饭，他会有点喜欢
I love it that the idea of relationship
我喜欢这种关系的想法
and so weird the question is you know
你知道这个问题很奇怪
where where he at Matt and have you
他在马特哪里有你
decided and just be quite honest this is
决定，只是说实话
dear Jesus I don't know everything about
亲爱的耶稣，我不知道有关的一切
you but I do know what I need in my life
你但我确实知道我生命中需要什么
I don't totally understand what's
我不完全明白是什么
women's I know I'm separated for me
女人我知道我和我分开了
because of what it is in my life and the
因为它在我的生活和生活中是什么
water would be healthy losses
水将是健康的损失
because I want you to know that it's not
因为我希望 你知道它不是
about having it all together I still
关于把它放在一起我还是
care for the understanding like totally
像完全一样关心理解
what spin is in my separation from God I
什么旋转在我与上帝的分离中我
know I and so we really encourage you
知道我，所以我们真的很鼓励你
I want to thank don't overthink it and
我要感谢不要过分思考它
yeah it's going to be the biggest
是的，这将是最大的
decision you've ever made in your entire
你在整个过程中做出的决定
life fingers you might even want to
你甚至可能想要的生活手指
thank my goodness what have I got myself
谢天谢地，我得到了什么
into the time and just like he was
进去的时候，只是喜欢他
faithful to know I he stapled up and as
忠实地知道我他已经订婚了
I was saying there pondering it because
我在说那是在考虑因为
Carrie and I took him some snacks to be
我和嘉莉带了他一些小吃
with us along the way and I said Carrie
和我们在一起，我说嘉莉
just like God provided the arm for Noah
就像上帝 为挪亚 提供了 一臂之力
jesus is our arms in this world when we
当我们这个世界，耶稣是我们的武器
choose to ask Jesus to come into our
选择让耶稣进入我们的
part that the life-giving portion of our
我们的生命部分
life where you know that our inner man
生活，你知道我们内心的人
our inner person then basically we
我们内心的人基本上就是我们
choose to come under his covering and we
我选择接受他的承保
applied there we live there we do life
应用那里我们住在那里，我们做生活
with him until we are taken to heaven
与他同在，直到我们被带到天堂
and new earth which is so cool so I'm
和新地球这么酷，所以我
sitting there going down jesus is our
坐在那里下来耶稣是我们的
art because it said if you abide in me
艺术， 因为它说如果你住在我身边
right you abide in me and so it's like
对，你住在我身边就是这样
and so cool and it's a white jesus is
太酷了，这是一个白色的耶稣
our art in this world for those of us
我们这个世界上的艺术对我们这些人来说
who have chosen to come in ray come in
谁选择进入射线进来
the door yeah and then I love about that
门是啊然后我喜欢那个
is God closes a door he keeps em stand
是上帝关上了他一直站着的门
with him
和他在一起
so you know that was just one of those
所以你知道那 只是其中之一
like really cheap like wow wow moment
喜欢真的很便宜，就像哇哇哇哇
yeah yeah like just so very cool
是的， 是的，非常酷
yeah so many things to think about
是的， 要考虑很多事情
and when we talked about how
当我们谈论如何
it's kind of like the exhibit within the
它有点像在展览中
art and it gave more reason for why this
艺术和它给了更多理由为什么这样
happened why it was plausible okay okay
发生了为什么它似乎有道理没关系好吧
but if I was an outsider I was walking
但如果我是一个局外人，我就走路了
through this as someone who was not a
通过这个作为一个不是 一个人
Christian well what I think and at one
基督徒很好，我认为和在一个
point I kind of look it came to like
点我看起来 喜欢
believable it's almost like unbelievable
可信， 这几乎是令人难以置信的
and how to think that that happened it
以及如何认为发生这种情况
could happen today and the logistics of
可能发生在今天和物流
it God really fluffy furs and there is
它上帝真的很蓬松，有
all this evidence
所有这些证据
but the most one of the most salient
但最突出的一个
points for me was this exhibit of the
我点了这个展览的
woman pondering the tough questions the
女人思考这个棘手的问题
wives of life and seeing the door there
生活的妻子，看到那里的门
and at the end of the day the question
并在一天结束时的问题
is what are you going to do is right
你打算做什么是正确的
here is God making away for you and
这是上帝为你而生
what's going to be your response some
什么是你的回应
things are true whether we believe them
无论我们是否相信它们都是事实
or not that is so true if it's raining
如果下雨 ，那是不是真的如此
is raining if it's flooded it's flooded
如果它被洪水淹没，它正在下雨
if I'd spend at students yeah and I look
如果我花在学生上是的，我看
in my own heart and I know what to be
在我自己的心里，我知道该是什么
queuing I look around at the wickedness
排队我四处看看邪恶
of the world and I know it to be true
世界，我知道这是真的
and so
所以
you know when when the Bible says
你知道什么时候圣经说
there's no other other name under heaven
天下没有别的名字
given unto men by which he can be seen
给予他可以被看见的人
there is no other way so whether you're
没有别的办法，所以不管你是不是
looking at it as a Christian or or
把它视为 基督徒或或
someone who's never heard of right the
一个从未听说过的人
question that you're left with at the
你留下的问题
end is still the same what are you going
什么是你要去的结局仍然是一样的
to do is write and
要做的就是写和
you know as the image of that woman that
你知道那个女人的形象
she's just sleeping and thinking and
她只是在睡觉，思考着
itself is God John in doing this we know
我们知道，这本身就是上帝 约翰
it
它
the answers yes yep it's just because
答案是的，是的， 这只是因为
his heart is that we would be a
他的心是我们会 成为的
relationship with him ultimately yeah
与他的关系最终是的
and so for those people they had
对于那些有他们的人
opportunity to have relationship with
与...有机会的机会
God when they chose not to because the
上帝当他们选择不去因为
Bible continues to be clear that was
圣经继续显而易见
like you want all people to be saved
就像你希望所有人都得救
and and the fact that he provided a way
而且他提供了一个方法
out because at any point in time any one
因为在任何时间任何一个
of them could have come to Noah and send
他们可能来到 诺亚并派遣
know what are you doing I'm building an
知道你在做什么我正在建设一个
ark for God because of the wickedness of
为了上帝的方舟，因为邪恶
this world and everyone will be
这个世界，每个人都会
any one of them could have said I
他们中的任何一个都可以说我
believe you I mean I'm a min but nobody
相信你我的意思是我是一个分钟，但没有人
did because no one was righteous except
是因为没有人是正义的，除了
for Noah and they had 100 years what the
诺亚和他们有100年的时间
way the fact that it took so long it's
它花了这么长时间的事实
like an extension of God's great ruling
就像是上帝伟大统治的延伸
this is the prophets in the Old
这是旧时的先知
Testament were told to actually
遗嘱被告知实际上
physically do things as a representing
身体做事作为代表
God's coming judgment you know like
上帝即将到来的判断，你知道
Ezekiel or Jeremiah they were giving up
以西结或耶利米他们放弃了
these calls verbally but they were also
这些电话口头但他们也是
doing things like kind of acting things
做一些像表演的事情
out so it was like Noah's they could see
所以这就像诺亚他们能看到的那样
this big monument this big Park and for
这座大公园和这座大型纪念碑
a hundred years it was being built and
它正在建造一百年
I'm sure over the 100 years those
我相信这100年了
families of the people in that area
该地区人民的家庭
would have had children and the kids
会有孩子和孩子
have been like was back yeah oh that's
已经像是回来了哦哦那是
Noah oh that's that crazy guy out you
诺啊，那个疯狂的家伙
know yeah but he so did it yes
知道是的，但他是这样做的
and
和
you're right it was a hundred years
你是对的， 这是一百年
there for people to make a choice and we
那里有人做出选择而我们
had the communion at church he weeks ago
他几个星期前在教堂做过圣餐
and said to my people I said you don't
并对我的人说，我说你没有
Jesus gave his life for us
耶稣为我们献出了生命
if you have not made a choice to serve
如果你还没有选择 服务
him today today is the day like don't
他今天今天是不喜欢的日子
print off but don't think you have a
打印，但不认为你有
hundred years like Noah or don't think
百年像诺亚或不思考
well it won't rain that's how I again
好吧，不会再下雨了
right it has never raised before so they
对，它从来没有提过，所以他们
just made the assumption well no that's
只是做出了很好的假设
not gonna happen not going to happen but
不会发生不会发生但是
just like Kari spec just because you
就像卡里规范一样，因为你
don't believe something is true does not
不相信某事是真的没有
mean it's not sure thing and so
意味着它不确定，所以
you know I've been sitting here today
你知道我今天 一直坐在这里
after he wagging become our shoulders a
他摇摇头后成了我们的肩膀
lot about my insurance machines as well
很多关于我的保险 机器
the answer is gifted
答案很有天赋
instead so scary and I have both made a
相反如此可怕，我已经做了一个
position to follow Christ certain with
坚定地跟随基督的位置
our lives is that he committed to
我们的生活就是他所承诺的
telling other people about how amazing
告诉其他人有多神奇
and awesome sighs because he loves you
因为 他爱你， 所以叹了口气
because he is cooked and intelligence
因为他熟食和智慧
surrender your life to Christ you will
你会将你的生命交给基督
never believe of experience love and
永远不要相信经验的爱和
acceptance and purpose and applauding
接受，目的和鼓掌
so you have to show my seem like a
所以你必须表现出我的样子
little bit heavier today unlike okay
今天有点重，不像好吧
where are you at with Jesus is the story
你和 耶稣 在哪里是 故事
so a really really got me thinking about
所以真的让我想到了
those idea like God extends his grace to
像上帝这样的想法延伸了他的恩典
us we have got to pick it up even yeah
我们必须接受它 ， 即使是的
so leaning on that note we're just going
我只是靠着那张纸条走了
to pray with you and we'll have a lot
和你一起祷告， 我们会有很多
more to talk about as we have different
我们有更多不同的话题
adventures on our trip so why don't we
我们旅行的冒险所以我们为什么不这样做
pray father
祈祷父亲
just want to thank you that you are both
只想感谢你们两个都是
just and good yes and kind
公正，善良，善良
and that you didn't just send someone to
并且你不只是派人去
be the sacrifice you yourself Jane
是你自己的牺牲简
and the person of Jesus Christ to be
和耶稣基督的人要
that door and I thank you that we offer
那扇门，我感谢你们 提供的
that to us
那对我们来说
at the end of the day
在一天结束时
you are the way and I pray for all the
你就是这样，我为所有人祈祷
people watching or listening
人们在看或听
you would pull them to yourself god
你会把它们拉到自己的 神
is it going to a storm in their life
是否会成为他们生活中的风暴
right now helping before on to you the
现在正在帮助你
year the anchor for our school and so
一年是我们学校的主播等等
much more and we pray this in the name
更多，我们在名义上祈祷
thank you so much for tuning in I'm
非常感谢你对我进行调整
really enjoyed the time to stop and
真的很享受停下来的时间
think just like that that model of
就像那个模特那样思考
something
某物
while she was sleeping and whatever ever
当她在睡觉时，无论如何
your at you need some time stopping me
你需要一些时间阻止我
yes where am I asked though have an
是的我在哪里问我有没有
amazing week and we will see you next
惊人的一周，我们接下来会见到你
week for more adventures in the United
本周将有更多的美国冒险经历
States oh really
哦哦，真的
[Music]
[音乐]
you
您